Diamond, Ann Pecora, 1946-. Papers of Ann Pecora Diamond, 1897-2009 (inclusive), 1946-2009 (bulk): A Finding Aid
Papers of Ann Pecora Diamond, 1897-2009 (inclusive), 1946-2009 (bulk)
- Series II. CORRESPONDENCE, 1957-2009 (#15.3-39.7)
  - Jo Ann Rumino, 1991-1996, 32.10.
  - Barbara Rutherford, 1983, 32.11.
  - Sakia [New Haven, Connecticut, store], 1995-1997, 32.12.
  - Bonnie Sargent, 1993-1994, n.d., 32.13.
  - Bobbie Seidenstein, 1989-1995 (2 folders), 32.14-33.1.
  - Mary and Bob Sherwood, 1983-2006, 33.2.
  - Lionel Simpson, 1996, 33.3.
  - [Social Security benefits, 2000], 33.4.
  - Veronica Soell, 1991-2009, 33.5-33.6.
  - Virginia Simon, 1996-1997, 33.7.
  - Patricia Spacks, 1989-1992, 33.8.
  - Charles Spector, 1983-1988, n.d., 33.9.
  - St. Francis Home for Children, 2005-2008, 33.10.
  - Caroline Stacey, 1993-1996, 33.11.
  - Patricia Stacy, 1990, 33.12.
  - Joey Taylor [formerly Joey Kurtz], 1975-2008, n.d., 33.13.
  - Mark Vickers, 1983, 33.14.
  - Freda White, 1970-1977, 33.15.
  - Andrew Wilkie, 1983-1994, 33.16.
  - Dennie Williams, 2001, 34.1.
  - Vicky Wirth, 1994-2006, 34.2.
  - Julie Womack, 2007-2009, 34.3.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2002, 34.4-34.6.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2003, 34.7-34.11.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2004, 35.1-35.4.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2005, 35.5-35.7.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2006 (3 folders), 35.8-36.1.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2007, 36.2-36.4.
  - Jonas Zdanys, 2008, 36.5.
  - Susan Zucker, 2002-2008, 36.6-36.7.
  - [Correspondence, 1964-1969], 36.8.
  - [Correspondence, 1970-1974], 36.9.
  - [Correspondence, 1975-1977], 36.10.
  - [Correspondence, 1978-1985], 36.11.
  - [Correspondence, 1986-1987], 37.1.
  - [Correspondence, 1988-1989], 37.2.
  - [Correspondence, 1990], 37.3-37.4.
  - [Correspondence, 1991], 37.5.
  - [Correspondence, 1992], 37.6.
  - [Correspondence, 1993], 37.7.
  - [Correspondence, 1994], 37.8.
  - [Correspondence, 1995], 37.9.
  - [Correspondence, 1996], 37.10.
  - [Correspondence, 1997], 37.11.
  - [Correspondence, 1998], 37.12.
  - [Correspondence, 1999], 37.13.
  - [Correspondence, 2000 (3 folders)], 37.14-38.1.
  - [Correspondence, 2001], 38.2-38.3.
  - [Correspondence, 2002; includes uncataloged photographs], 38.4.
  - [Correspondence, 2003], 38.5.
  - [Correspondence, 2004], 38.6.
  - [Correspondence, 2005], 38.7.
  - [Correspondence, 2006], 38.8.
  - [Correspondence, 2007], 38.9.
  - [Correspondence, 2008], 38.10-38.12.
  - [Correspondence, 2009], 39.1.
  - [Correspondence, n.d.], 39.2-39.7.
- Series III. DIAMOND V. YALE UNIVERSITY, 1967-2002 (#39.8-58.6, T-364.2 - T-364.5, Vt-170.2)
  - Age discrimination, 1993, 39.8.
  - Sue Alkins, 1995, 39.9.
  - American Association of Retired Persons (AARP), 1993-1996, 39.10.
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW) legal advisory fund, 1994, 39.11.
  - Vincent Anastasio, witness to my moving out of my office, 1993, 39.12.
  - Jay Angeletti projects, 1993, 39.13.
  - Jay Angeletti meeting audiotapes, 1993., T-364.2 - T-364.3.
    REQUEST AS T-364, reels 2-3.
  - Joanne Anderson, 1993, 39.14.
  - Appellate court: brief of plaintiff-appellant and index, 2000, 39.15.
  - Awards, 1990-1993; includes uncataloged photographs, 40.1.
  - Awards: videotape of CASE award ceremony, 1993., Vt-170.2.
    REQUEST AS Vt-170, reel 2.
  - Pat Bahnsen, 1993-1996, 40.2.
  - David Baker, 1994, 40.3.
  - Bass family, 1994-1997, 40.4.
  - Esther Bauman, 1995-1996, 40.5.
  - Merle Berke-Schessel, administrative judges for Connecticut Commission on Human Rights and Opportunities (CCHRO),1997, 40.6.
  - Bill Bidwell, 1994, 40.7.
  - James Blanning, n.d., 40.8.
  - John Borden, 1994, 40.9.
  - Leo Breiman, 1995, 40.10.
  - Judith Burch, 1994-1996, 40.11.
  - Dean Gerard Burrow, 1995-1997, 40.12.
  - Pat Caplan, former secretary, 1994, 40.13.
  - Jackie Civitillo, 1995, 40.14.
  - Jon Clune, 1993-1998, 40.15.
  - Dr. Lawrence Cohen, 1992, 40.16.
  - Mike Coleman, 1988-1995, 40.17.
  - Dr. James Comer, 1994, 40.18.
  - Confidentiality agreement, 1997, 40.19.
  - Connecticut Commission on Human Rights and Opportunities (CCHRO), 1992-1995, 40.20.
  - Connecticut Supreme Court, 2001-2002, 40.21.
  - Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund, 1996, 40.22.
  - Nancy Cott, n.d., 40.23.
  - Court orders, 1994-1997, 40.24.
  - Court transcript, Superior Court, Judicial District of New Haven-Civil Matters, docket #CV94356256S, 1999 (16 folders), 40.25-42.6.
  - Dolores Cullen, 1991, 42.7.
  - Daily harassment, part I, 1991-1993, 42.8.
  - Daily harassment, part II, 1993, 42.9.
  - Daily harassment, part III, 1993, 43.1.
  - Defendants pleadings, 1996-1997, 43.2.
  - Sheila Dennis, 1994, 43.3.
  - Diamond deposition, 1997, 43.4-43.6.
  - Diamond deposition [background], 1993-1999 (3 folders), 43.7-44.1.
  - Diamond deposition notes, ca.1997, 44.2.
  - Diamond memos re: various projects at work, 1985-1993, 44.3.
  - [Diamond notes, n.d.], 44.4.
  - Diamond notes, retaliation notes, 1992-1993, 44.5.
  - [Diamond promotion history, 1989-1993], 44.6.
  - Diamond (Yale's production) [office memos], 1987-1996 (2 folders), 44.7-45.1.
  - [Diamond Yale work] Medparty/holiday cards, etc., 1991-1993, 45.2.
  - Discharge/severance pay, 1993, 45.3.
  - Dr. Lewis Downing, 1997, 45.4.
  - Eric Eitel, 1993, 45.5.
  - Emotional damages, 1992-1998, 45.6.
  - Fabrication of grade, 1988, 45.7.
  - Fan mail, 1972-1993, 45.8.
  - Federal case, 1995-1997, 45.9.
  - David Finley, 1996, 45.10.
  - First and second warning letters, 1989-1993, 46.1.
  - Margaret Forbes, 1994-1998, 46.2.
  - Deborah Fried: the shrink from hell, 1993-1997, 46.3.
  - Marge Funk, 1995-1997, 46.4.
  - Marge Funk deposition, 1997, 46.5.
  - Jeff Glaser, 1993-1994, 46.6.
  - Grievance, 1992-1993, 46.7.
  - Grievance filing, 1998-1999, 46.8.
  - Grievance portfolio, 1988-1993 (3 folders), 46.9-47.2.
  - Doug Hawthorne, 1997, 47.3.
  - Judge Thelton Henderson, 1992-1997, 47.4.
  - Joy Hirsch, 1993-1994, 47.5.
  - Terry Holcombe, 1988-1998, 47.6.
  - Fran Holloway, 1992-1995, 47.7.
  - Ellen Hope-Ross, 1994-1997, 47.8.
  - Hospital ball, 1991-1992, 47.9.
  - Tracy Hughes deposition, 1998, 47.10.
  - Nadya Jakovenko, 1997, 47.11.
  - Shelley Jerige, 1991, 47.12.
  - Job descriptions/postings, 1989-1993, 47.13.
  - Job search efforts, 1994-1998, 48.1.
  - Phyllis Joffe, n.d., 48.2.
  - Jury charges, 1996, 48.3.
  - Dean David Kessler, 1997, 48.4.
  - William Kissick, 1989-1993, 48.5.
  - Susan Sanzone Kovacs, 1991-1994, 48.6.
  - Sharon Krischtshun, 1998, 48.7.
  - Pamela La Regina, 1997, 48.8.
  - Mrs. James Lamb, 1993-1994, 48.9.
  - Legal filings, 1993-2000, 48.10-48.12.
  - Legal research, 1996-1997, 49.1.
  - Letters of recognition, 1985-1993, 49.2.
  - Richard Levin, 1993-1996, 49.3.
  - Dr. Gustaf Lindskog, 1990, 49.4.
  - Litigation file, 1994-1998, 49.5-49.6.
  - Phillip Mancini, 1993-1995, 49.7.
  - Carol Martin, 1994-1995, 49.8.
  - Kitty Matzkin, 1988-1997, 49.9.
  - Sharon McManus, 1993-1995, 49.10.
  - Medicaid, 1998, 49.11.
  - Medical records/expenses, 1995-1999, 49.12.
  - Medical records: Yale Health Plan records, 1987-1993, 49.13.
  - Medparty review, n.d., 49.14.
  - Will Melton, 1987-1993, 49.15.
  - Will Melton deposition, 1997 (2 folders), 49.16-50.1.
  - Will Melton, history with, 1987-1991, 50.2.
  - Memos/personal letters, 1987-1994, 50.3.
  - Merit increase and letters of support, 1987-1993, 50.4.
  - Miscellaneous work memos, 1987-1993; includes uncataloged photographs (#50.5), 50.5-50.6.
  - Barbara Moynihan, 1993-1998, 50.7-50.8.
  - Barbara Moynihan deposition, 1997-1998, 50.9-50.10.
  - Dr. Bill Monroe, 1995, 51.1.
  - Bishop Paul Moore, n.d., 51.2.
  - C.J. Mozzochi, 1997, 51.3.
  - Lynne Neumon deposition, 1998, 51.4.
  - 1984 hiring, 1990 promotion, 1991 downgrading and appeal, 1987-1992, 51.5.
  - Non-promotion, 1992, 51.6.
  - [Notebook] volume I, 1972-1993, 51.7-51.8.
  - [Notebook] volume II, 1991-1994; notes, 1999 (3 folders), 51.9-52.2.
  - [Notebook] volume III, 1992-1993, 52.3-52.5.
  - [Notebook] volume IV, 1984-1993, 53.1-53.3.
  - Notes/Ann direct, 1991-1999, 53.4.
  - David Nowak, n.d., 53.5.
  - Office accounts, 1992-1993, 53.6.
  - Office diary [handwritten original], 1989, 53.7.
  - Office diaries [typed], 1989-1994 (3 folders), 53.8-54.2.
  - Dr. John Ogilvie, 1991-1994, 54.3.
  - Barbara Orrok [psychiatrist], 1995-1998, 54.4.
  - Barbara Orrok [psychiatrist] deposition, 1998-1999, 54.5-54.6.
  - Other job applications at Yale, 1982-1990, 54.7.
  - Charlie Pagnam, 1995-1997, 54.8.
  - Helaine Patterson, 1993-1998, 54.9.
  - Charles Paul, 1996, 54.10.
  - David Pecora, 1988-1998, 54.11.
  - Dorothy Pecora, 1993-1995; includes uncataloged photographs, 54.12.
  - Michele Pecora, 1994; includes uncataloged photographs, 54.13.
  - Penny Peoples, 1990-1998, 54.14.
  - Personnel/office, 1984-1992, 55.1.
  - Wendell Piehler, 1994-1998, 55.2.
  - Plaintiff pleadings, 1994-1997, 55.3.
  - Plaintiff's exhibits, 1987-1990, 55.4.
  - Robert Porta deposition, 1999, 55.5.
  - Rebecca Poyourow, 1994, 55.6.
  - Pre-development office Yale employment, 1978-1988, 55.7.
  - Pre-Yale work, 1967-1981, 55.8.
  - Press coverage and contacts, 1993-1998, 55.9.
  - Press coverage: audiotape: Connecticut Public Radio's show "Faith Middleton," "Mary" is Ann Diamond, November 2, 1993., T-364.4.
    REQUEST AS T-364, reel 4.
  - Press coverage: audiotape: National Public Radio, March 1994, T-364.5.
    REQUEST AS T-364, reel 5.
  - Questionnaire [re: stewardship at other universities], 1991, 55.10.
  - Retaliation, 1992-1993, 55.11-55.13.
  - Right to sue letter, 1995, 55.14.
  - Michele Komola Rockford, 1994-1995, 55.15.
  - Dean Leon Rosenberg, 1989-1995; includes uncataloged photographs, 56.1.
  - Bonnie Sargent, 1993-1997, 56.2.
  - Susanne Schall, 1987-1988, 56.3.
  - Richard Silva, 1992-1997, 56.4.
  - Abigail Smith, 1994-1997, 56.5.
  - Lois Smith, 1994-1996, 56.6.
  - Social Security disability, 1998, 56.7.
  - Regina Starolis, 1992, 56.8.
  - Stress induced illness, 1993, 56.9.
  - Time records, 1978-1992, 56.10.
  - Connie Tolliver, 1998, 56.11.
  - Unemployment, 1993, 56.12.
  - Peter Vallone, 1993-1996, 56.13.
  - Robert Venturi, 1992, 56.14.
  - Merle Waxman and Steve Waxman discrimination complaint at Connecticut Commission on Human Rights and Opportunities (CCHRO), 1992-1997, 56.15.
  - Sheila Wellington, 1987-1994, 56.16.
  - Mrs. John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1990-1998, 56.17.
  - Witness depositions, 1992-1998, 56.18-56.19.
  - Yale personnel manual, effective during Diamond's tenure, 1987, 57.1.
  - Yale School of Medicine holiday card, 1986-1993, 57.2.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1985-1991], 57.3.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1992], 57.4.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1993], 57.5-57.6.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1994], 57.7.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1995-1996], 57.8.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1997], 57.9.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1998], 58.1.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 1999], 58.2-58.3.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 2000], 58.4.
  - [Correspondence found loose, 2001-2002], 58.5.
  - [Correspondence found loose, n.d.], 58.6.
- Series IV. FAMILY PAPERS, 1897, 1932-2004 (#58.7-60.10, PD.1)
  - Ruby Beavers: letters from Diamond, 1971-1991; includes uncataloged photographs, 58.7.
  - Philippo Muzi: Italian railway pass, 1897; includes uncataloged photographs, 58.8.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1967-1969, 58.9.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1970, 59.1.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1971, 59.2-59.3.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1972, 59.4.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1973, 59.5.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1974., 59.6.
    Includes reference copies of photographs; originals filed in #PD.1.
  - Photographs removed from #59.6 (3 photographs), PD.1.
    FILED WITH PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1975, 59.7.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1976, 59.8-59.9.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1977, 59.10.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1978, 60.1.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1979, 60.2.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1980, 60.3.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1981, 60.4.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, 1982, 60.5.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from Diamond, n.d., 60.6.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora: letters from friends and family, 1956-2004, n.d., 60.7.
  - David Pecora autobiography, Between the Raindrops, 1998, 60.8.
  - David Pecora high school medals, 1932-1933, 60.9.
  - David Pecora Yale commencement, 1941, 60.10.
- Series V. PHOTOGRAPHS, ca.1918, 1950-1990 (#PD.2-PD.9)
  #PD.1 contains photographs found with other documents. Photographs were removed and foldered separately, and the folder is listed in Series IV.
  - Ann Pecora Diamond, 1950-1990; includes Betty Grover Eisner (20 photographs), PD.2.
  - Ann Pecora Diamond childhood and teenage years photograph album, 1954-1964 (140 photographs), PD.3f+.
  - Ann Pecora Diamond portrait, ca.1967; Ann Pecora Diamond and commune, ca.1970 (2 photographs), PD.4f.
  - Ann Pecora Diamond and commune, 1972-1979; includes David B. Eisner (16 photographs), PD.5.
  - Ann Pecora Diamond and Stephen Diamond, 1967-1969; includes wedding portrait (4 photographs), PD.6.
  - Ann Pecora Diamond and Michele Pecora, 1964-1976 (10 photographs), PD.7.
  - David and Dorothy Pecora, ca.1918, 1960s-1990s (10 photographs), PD.8.
  - Pecora family, 1960s (6 photographs), PD.9.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Authors
Eisner, Betty Grover, 1915-
Eisner, David B.
McCann, Les, 1935-
Pecora, David V. (David Victor), 1916-
Pecora, Dorothy Beavers
Pecora, Michele
Subjects
Ageism--United States
Audiotapes
Baby books
Communal living--California
Diaries
Divorce--United States
Fathers and daughters--United States
Legal documents
Manuscripts for publication
Mental illness--Alternative treatment
Mothers and daughters--United States
New Haven (Conn.)--Social life and customs--20th century
Parent and child--United States
Photographs
Psychotherapists--Malpractice--California
Psychotherapy--California
Rolfing--Personal narratives
Santa Monica (Calif.)--Social life and customs--20th century
Scrapbooks
Sex discrimination against women--United States
Sex discrimination in employment--United States
Videotapes
Yale University--Employees
Yale University--Trials, litigation, etc.
SEPARATION RECORD
Donors: Ann Pecora Diamond
Accession numbers: 2000-M156, 2001-M66, 2002-M22, 2003-M49, 2004-M1, 2005-M18, 2007-M30, 2009-M68
Processed by: Johanna Carll
The following item has been transferred to the Schlesinger Library books and printed materials collection (pending review by curator):
TREEO: Training in Equal Employment Opportunity, compiled and published by St. Pierre Associates, 1977
The following item has been transferred to the Schlesinger Library calendar collection (Gr-16):
The Women's Memorial special edition calendar honoring women pioneers of World War I, 1996